<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<EventSection>
	<inter_university>
		<literary>
			<Event name="English Debate">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>English Debate</Strong></center>
				<strong>Team Size:</strong> 2 from each University/College, one for the motion & the other against the motion<br/>
				<strong>Time limit:</strong> Each member will be given 4 minutes to speak and 1 minute to refute. The refutation shall begin with the last speaker. 1st warning Buzzer will be after 3 minutes.<br/>
				<strong>Topic:</strong>
"Indian Media, as Fourth Pillar of Democracy, is not discharging its duty" <br/>
				1.	Topic will be available on the Resurgence website 2 days prior to the event or will be inform to your Manager.<br/>
				2.	Medium of presentation is English only.<br/>
				3.	Paper reading is not allowed. One may however refer to noted points.<br/>
				<strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Voice Modulation (including suitable use of accents), content, suitability and propriety of language<br/>
				Matter: the logical reasoning and content presented by the debater<br/>
				Manner: presentation and delivery, the style of speaking and body language.<br/>
				Method: structure and organization of the presentation made by the speakers.
				Refutation.
				]]>	
			</Event>
			<Event name="Hindi Debate">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong> Hindi Debate</Strong></center>
				<strong>Team Size:</strong> 3 from each University/College, one for the motion & the other against the motion<br/>
				<strong>Time limit:</strong> Each member will be given 4 minutes to speak and 1 minute to refute. The refutation shall begin with the last speaker. 1st warning Buzzer will be after 3 minutes.<br/>
				<strong>Topic:</strong>"भारतीय मीडिया लोकतंत्र के चौथे स्तम्भ के रूप में अपने कर्तव्यों का निर्वाह नहीं कर रही है" <br/>
				1.	Topic will be available on the Resurgence website 2 days prior to the event or will be inform to your Manager.<br/>
				2.	Medium of presentation is English only.<br/>
				3.	Paper reading is not allowed. One may however refer to noted points.<br/>
				<strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Voice Modulation (including suitable use of accents), content, suitability and propriety of language<br/>
				Matter: the logical reasoning and content presented by the debater<br/>
				Manner: presentation and delivery, the style of speaking and body language.<br/>
				Method: structure and organization of the presentation made by the speakers.
				Refutation.
				]]>	
			</Event>
			<Event name="Group Extempore">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Group Extempore</Strong></center>
				<strong>Team Size:</strong> 3 from each University/College<br>
				<strong>Time limit:</strong> 2 minutes for each participant<br>
				1.	Topic will be announced on the spot. <br>
				2.	For each team there will be a different topic. <br/>
				3.	The first speaker shall begin speaking after 2 minutes of getting the topic.<br/>
				4.	Each participant of a team will be given 2 minutes. <br/>
				5.	After 2 minutes, there will be a Buzzer and the next member will take over where the last speaker finishes.<br/><br>
				<strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Creativity, Spontaneity, Body language, Voice modulation, intensity and coverage of the content
				]]>

			</Event>
			<Event name="Quiz">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Quiz</Strong></center></strong>
				<strong>Team Size:</strong> 3 from each house.<br>

				Rules: 1. The Quiz will be based on the following topics:
             	Science, Geog., History & Culture, Sports, Current Affairs<br>
	
          		2. The Specific rules regarding evaluation procedure, time to reply a particular answer
            	and the type of round will be given before the actual start of the competition.
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Poetry">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Poetry</Strong></center></strong>
				<strong>Team Size:</strong> 2 (1 for English and 1 for Hindi) from each House<br>
				<strong>Time limit: </strong>3-5 minutes for each recitation <br>
				1. Topic will be given only two hours before the event and the participant is required to write poetry in a place specified by the event coordinators. <br>
				2. Medium of poetry is English and Hindi (although restricted use of Urdu may be allowed).<br>
				3. The participant will have to submit the content of the poem in writing to the judges after the recitation.<br>
				<strong>Judging Criteria:<strong> Choice of words, diction, creativity, and style of recitation, relevance to the theme<br>
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Essay Writing">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Essay Writing</Strong></center></strong>
				<stong>Team Size:</strong> 2 (individual) from each House<br>
				<strong>Time limit:</Strong> 2 hours.<br>
				1. The topic will be announced on the spot. <br>
				2. The essay should reflect participant’s point of view.<br>
				3. The essay should be between 300-600 words.	<br>
				4. The language of writing is English/Hindi.<br>
				<Strong>Judging criteria:</Srtong><br>
				1. Language<br>
				2. Articulation<br>
				3. Argumentation and Justification.<br>
				4. Counter arguments and their criticism.<br>
				5. A viable conclusion.
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Creative Writing">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Creative Writing</Strong></center></strong><br>
				Team Size: 2 from each House<br>
					<strong>Time limit:</stong> 3 hours.
					1. The situation/theme and first line of the story will be announced on the spot. <br>
					2. The participants are required to make a well-formed, original story. The situation/theme may belong to any time, any era, any place, and any culture. The level of expression must appropriate the character of the situation/theme.<br>
					3. The story should be of 500 – 1200 words.<br>
					4. The language of writing can be English/Hindi.<br>
					<strong>Judging criteria:</strong><br><br>
					1. Ability to captivate the reader till the end <br>
					2. Originality and articulation.<br>
				]]>
			</Event>
		</literary>
		<music>
			<Event name="Sangam">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Sangam</Strong></center>
					<strong>Team Size:</strong> 	5-8 including the accompanist.<br>
					<strong>Time limit:<strong> 	6-10 minutes (including setup and clearance time)<br>

					<Strong>Rules:</strong><br>
					1. A team member can sing and play an instrument as well. However such a person would be counted as both vocalist and accompanist. <br>
					2. Only Piano mode in key board is allowed, touch sense is allowed in keyboard and guitars will have to be played in clean mode. No processing of any kind including distortion will be allowed.  <br>
					3. Time Limit should be strictly followed. Participants will be penalized by judges for not doing so. <br>
					4. The decision of the organizers with respect to line-up would be final. <br>
					5. The decision of the judges will be binding.<br>
					6. The team may sing more than one song within the time limit.<br>
					7. Karaoke not allowed.<br><br>

					<Strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Content, Delivery and quality of Vocals, Presentation, Synchronization, Stage presence and overall performance as a group.
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Light Indian Vocal">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Light Indian Vocal</Strong></center></strong>
		
				<Strong>Team Size: </strong>1 participant from each house + 5 accompanists (max)<br>
				<strong>Dress Code:</strong> Contestants are asked to wear appropriate attire to the competition.<br>
				<strong>Time limit: </strong>3-5 minutes for performance + 3 minutes for set up and clearance<br>
				<strong>Instruments Provided:</strong> 2 Guitars, 1 Bass, 1 Drum Kit, 1 Synthesizer and 1 Tabla-set<br>
				1. The participants are required to come prepared with a song of their choice to showcase their versatility.<br>
				2. Ghazal/bhajan/shabad/Sufi and Abhangas can be presented.<br>
				3. Karaoke not allowed.<br>
				4. Accompanists from other houses are allowed.<br><br>
 
      
				<strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Judgment is on the qualities like Swara, Taal, Innovation, Synchronization, Selection of Raga, Composition and Overall Impression.
				]]>
			</Event>

			<Event name="Western Vocal">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Western Vocals</Strong></center></strong><br>
		
					<Strong>Team Size:</strong> 1-2 from each House +5 accompanists (max)<br>
					<strong>Dress Code: </strong>Contestants are asked to wear appropriate attire to the competition.<br>
					<strong>Time limit:<strong> 3-5 minutes for performance + 3 minutes for set up and clearance<br>
					<strong>Instruments Provided:</strong> 2 Guitars, 1 Bass Guitar, 1 Drum Kit and 1 Synthesizer.<br>
					1. Only Western songs with no classical tinge are allowed.<br>
					2. Genres can be anything ranging from Rock to Rap and from Death Metal to Soft Singing.<br>
					3. Language of the song can be anything excluding those of Indian Subcontinents.<br>
					4. Karaoke not allowed.<br>
					5. Accompanists from other houses are allowed.<br><br>

					<strong>Judging Criteria: </strong>Judgment is made on the qualities like rhythm, vocals, composition coordination and overall impression
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Hindi Duet">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Hindi Duet</Strong></center></strong>
		
					<strong>Team Size:</strong> 2 from each house + 5 accompanists (max)<br>
					<strong>Dress Code:</strong> Contestants are asked to wear appropriate attire to the competition.<br>
					<strong>Time Limit:<strong> 5 minutes for performance + 2 minutes for set up and clearance<br>
					<strong>Instruments Provided:</strong> 2 Guitars, 1 Bass, 1 Drum Kit, 1 Synthesizer and 1 Tabla-set<br>
					1. The participants have to come prepared with a song of their choice to showcase their versatility.<br>
					2. The songs must have Hindi lyrics.<br>
					3. Karaoke not allowed.<br>
					4. Accompanists from other houses are allowed.<br>



					<strong>Judging Criteria:<strong> Synchronization, Presentation, Rhythm, delivery and quality of vocals and overall impact<br>
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Instrumental">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Instrumental</Strong></center></strong><br>
		<br>
				<strong>Team Size:</strong> 2-10 participants from each house<br>
				<strong>Time Limit:</strong> 5-8 minutes for performance + 2 minutes for set up and clearance<br>
				<strong>Instruments provided:</strong> As per requirements. <br>
				(Participants may bring their own instruments but must inform to the music coordinators 2 days prior to the event).<br>
				1. The participants have to come prepared with an instrumental song (fusion is allowed).<br>
				2. In the use of any electronic keyboard, no pre-programmed music is allowed. <br>
				3. The contestant must create all sound live on stage.<br>
				4. Non-traditional instruments can be used.<br>
				5. Accompanists from other houses are not allowed.<br><br>

				<strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Melody, synchronization, audience response, stage presentation, creativity.

				]]>
			</Event>


		</music>
		<art>
			<Event name="Poster Making">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Poster Making</Strong></center></strong><br>
				<strong>Team size:</strong> 2(individual) from each house<br>
				<strong>Time limit: </strong>2 hrs<br>
				</strong>Materials provided: </strong>A2/A3 Cartridge<br>
				The participants are required to make a poster on the topic given on the spot within the stipulated time. The participants are free to use any medium. The poster should be self-explanatory. However, text can be used in such a way that it becomes part of the whole picture & not a separate caption/slogan.<br>
				</strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Concept, Original and creative approach, Overall effect<br>
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Face Painting">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Face Painting</Strong></center></strong><br>
				<strong>Team size:</strong> 2 participant from each University/College (one model and one painter)<br/>
				<strong>Time limit:</strong> 2 hours<br/>
				<strong>Materials:</strong> Any color medium of your choice<br/>
				Participant will be given a topic one hour before the event. The output should be in relevance with the topic given.<br/><br>
				<strong>Judging Criteria: </strong>Concept, Overall effect
				]]>
			</Event>

			<Event name="Sketching">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Sketching</Strong></center></strong>
					<strong>Team Size:</strong> 1 individual from one house.<br>
					<strong>Time limit:</strong> 2:30 hrs<br>
					<strong>Material:</strong> Sheet will be provided. You need get your own pencil and other required stuff. And of course no color is allowed.<br>
					<strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Vision, Perspective, Accuracy to the scene given or towards the topic.<br>
					Control over lines and the strokes.<br>
					Sketch, need to be clean and not confusing, bold indeed.<br>

				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Logo Making">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Logo Making</Strong></center></strong>
				Team Size: 1 from each house<br>
					Time: 2 Hours<br>
					General Rules:<br>
					1. Logo should contain basic Primary figures. (Square, circle, triangle etc.)<br>
					2. Logo should be in 2D and 3D formats.<br>
					3. Primary colors (Red, Green, Blue, and Yellow) including Black and white can be used.<br>
					4. Logo should be handmade.<br>
					5. Logo should be in appropriate size.  (15cm x 15cm).<br>
					6. Logo may consist of icon, text, etc.<br>
					7. Logo may consist of any particular Font Style.<br>
					8. Description of logo design should also be submitted in 50 Words.<br>
					P.S. Wining logo should be given a chance to be a part of any event logo or could be 
					Published.<br><br>
					Judging Criteria: Concept, Color composition, Relevance to the theme, Neatness, 
					Finesse.<br>
				]]>
			</Event>

			<Event name="Model Making">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Model Making</Strong></center></strong>
				Team Size: 2(individuals) from each house<br>
					Time: 2 hrs<br>
					Material: two ivory will be provided, <br>
					but you need to get cutter, glue and other drafting material of your own.
					Topic will be given on the spot.<br><br>

					Judging Criteria: Perfection, Cleanliness of Model, and Closeness to the given topic.
					Further innovation on the topic would be helped by Fine Arts Coordinator. 

				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Clay Modeling">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Clay Modeling</Strong></center></strong>
				
					<em>Model carved should not be a composition of different blocks but a single unit.
					No reinforcement should be used. (Like pins or sticks)</em><br>
					Team size: 2 (individual) from each House<br>
					Time limit: 2 Hours.<br>
					Medium: Clay, POP.<br>
					Materials provided: Clay, POP (Plaster Of Paris).<br>
					Participant will be given a topic on the spot. The output should be self-explanatory.<br><br>
					Judging Criteria: Neatness, Effectiveness of the depiction, Relevance to the topic<br>


				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Rangoli">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Rangoli</Strong></center></strong>
				
					Team size: Maximum of 4 from each house<br>
					Time limit: 2 hrs<br>
					Materials: Free to use any traditional Rangoli material (usage of the colors which deface the floor is not allowed)<br>
					Area provided: 1.2 m x 1.2 m <br>
					The participants will be given a space of 1.2mx1.2m in which they have to depict the topic given to them in the stipulated time. The participants will have to submit their version of topic in not more than 100 words to the event coordinator.<br>
					Judging Criteria: Concept, Color composition, Relevance to the theme, Neatness, Finesse<br>


				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Stippling">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Stippling</Strong></center></strong>
				
					Team Size: 2 from each house<br>
					Time Limit: 2 hours<br>
					Materials: Rotring Pen, Black ink only allowed (NOT TO BE PROVIDED BY COORDINATING TEAM)<br>
					Judging Criteria: Creativity, Overall Effect<br>



				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Road Painting">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Road Painting</Strong></center></strong>
				Team Size: 8 from each house<br>
				Time Limit: 5 hours<br>
				Size: <br>
				Materials: Chalk, Paint, Putty, Spray Paints, Distemper Paint<br>
				Judging Criteria: Relevance to theme, Concept, Overall Effect<br>




				]]>
			</Event>
		</art>
		<dance>
			<Event name="Desi Beat.">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Desi Beat.</Strong></center>
				Team Size		:	8-12<br>
						Style			:	Bollywood<br>
						Time Limit		:	5-8 mins (+1 min for stage setup and clearance)<br>
						GENERAL RULES:<br>
						1. Teams may use more than one song in their performance.<br>
						2. INDIAN CLASSICAL dance steps are NOT allowed in this performance.<br>
						3. Judging criteria includes Coordination, Expressions, feel of Bollywood by your performance and audience response.<br>
						4. Usage of props is allowed. These have to be brought by the participants themselves.<br>
						5. Teams are requested to submit their songs in .mp3 format only.<br>
						6. Teams must follow the time limits. Teams will be penalized heavily on their points for exceeding the time limit.<br>
						7. Any kind of fluid, flame, powder or heavy object is not allowed on the stage.<br>
						8. Obscenity of any kind is not allowed and will lead to immediate disqualification of the house.<br>
						9. The decision of the judges will be final and binding.<br>
						10. Stage Clearance must be done immediately by the house members, or the points will be deducted for the same.<br>



				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Semi Classical Solo">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Semi Classical Solo</Strong></center>
				Team Size		:	1<br>
				Style			:	Any Indian Classical Dance Form<br>
				Time Limit		:	3-5 mins (+1 min for stage setup and clearance)<br>
				GENERAL RULES<br><br>
				1. Teams may use more than one song in their performance.<br>
				2. Judging criteria includes Expressions, Coordination of steps with beats, Clarity in steps and audience response.<br>
				3. Usage of props is allowed. These have to be brought by the teams themselves.<br>
				4. Teams are requested to submit their songs in .mp3 format only.<br>
				5. Teams must follow the time limits. Teams will be penalized heavily on their points for exceeding the time limit.<br>
				6. Any kind of fluid, flame, powder or heavy object is not allowed on the stage.<br>
				7. Obscenity of any kind is not allowed and will lead to immediate disqualification of the house.<br>
				8. The decision of the judges will be final and binding.<br>
				9. Stage Clearance must be done immediately by the house members, or the points will be deducted for the same.<br>
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Folk Dance">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Nrittyangan</Strong></center>
				Team Size		:	8-12<br>
				Style			:	Folk<br>
				Time Limit		:	6-8 mins (+1 min for stage setup and clearance)<br>
				GENERAL RULES<br><br>
				1. Teams may use more than one song in their performance.<br>
				2. Judging criteria includes Coordination, Expressions and audience response.<br>
				3. Chits will be picked up by the house captains for the different folk dance performances.<br>
				4. There won’t be any extra points of live music.<br>
				5. Usage of props is allowed. These have to be brought by the teams themselves.<br>
				6. Teams are requested to submit their songs in .mp3 format only.<br>
				7. Teams must follow the time limits. Teams will be penalized heavily on their points for exceeding the time limit.<br>
				8. Any kind of fluid, flame, powder or heavy object is not allowed.<br>
				9. Obscenity of any kind is not allowed and will lead to immediate disqualification of the house.<br>
				10. The decision of the judges will be final and binding.<br>
				11. Stage Clearance must be done immediately by the house members, or the points will be deducted for the same.<br>

				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Street Dance">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Project Street Dance</Strong></center>
				
					Team Size		:	10-14<br>
					Style			:	Hip-hop<br>
					Time Limit		:	6-8 mins (+1 min for stage setup and clearance)<br>
					GENERAL RULES<br>
					1. Teams may use more than one song in their performance.<br>
					2. Judging criteria includes Coordination, incorporation of stunts and audience response.<br>
					3. Songs may contain Bollywood beats but the dance steps must totally be western style.<br>
					4. Usage of props is allowed. These have to be brought by the teams themselves.<br>
					5. Teams are requested to submit their songs in .mp3 format only.<br>
					6. Teams must follow the time limits. Teams will be penalized heavily on their points for exceeding the time limit.<br>
					7. Any kind of fluid, flame, powder or heavy object is not allowed.<br>
					8. Obscenity of any kind is not allowed and will lead to immediate disqualification of the house.<br>
					9. The decision of the judges will be final and binding.<br>
					10. Stage Clearance must be done immediately by the house members, or the points will be deducted for the same.<br>
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Dancing Duo">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Dancing Duo</Strong></center>
				
					Team Size		:	2<br>
					Style			:	Participant’s choice<br>
					Time Limit		:	3-5 mins (+1 min for stage setup and clearance)<br>
					GENERAL RULES<br><br>
					1. Teams may use more than one song in their performance.<br>
					2. Judging criteria includes Coordination, Expressions, and Variation in styles and audience response.<br>
					3. Usage of props is allowed. These have to be brought by the teams themselves.<br>
					4. Teams are requested to submit their songs in .mp3 format only.<br>
					5. Teams must follow the time limits. Teams will be penalized heavily on their points for exceeding the time limit.<br>
					6. Any kind of fluid, flame, powder or heavy object is not allowed on the stage.<br>
					7. Obscenity of any kind is not allowed and will lead to immediate disqualification of the house.<br>
					8. The decision of the judges will be final and binding.<br>
					9. Stage Clearance must be done immediately by the house members, or the points will be deducted for the same.<br>

				]]>
			</Event>
		</dance>
		<theature>
			<Event name="Skit">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Skit</Strong></center>
				Team Size: Upto 8 participants + 4 accompanists (max)<br>
				Time limit: 12-16 minutes (includes setup and clearance time)<br>
				1. Each presentation should have a title and a theme. <br>
				2. Medium of performing the Skit should be Hindi. <br>
				3. The Skit can involve multiple scenes and blackouts.<br>
				4. Backstage voice overs or sounds or narration are allowed during the Performance.<br>
				5. Background or Pre-recorded music is allowed.<br>
				Production material provided: 1 table, 2 chairs.<br>
				Any other production material has to be brought by the teams but the Organizers reserve the right to allow its use on the stage.<br>
				Judging Criteria: Presentation of the theme, Group co-ordination, Dialogue Delivery and Overall impact, Acting, Make-up and Costumes <br>according to the Act.
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Stage Drama">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Stage Drama</Strong></center>
				Team size: Upto 20 (participants + Accompanists).<br>
					Time Limit:  15-25 minutes.<br>
					1. Live music and Background music are allowed. <br>
					2. Main Dialogue or Statements should be delivered from Background (LIVE), Screaming and Yelling or Crying can be delivered on stage.<br>
					3. If using background music it should be made sure that there are no dialogues present in the music or negative marks accordingly will be rewarded.<br>
					Any other production material has to be brought by the teams but the Organizers reserve the right to allow its use on the stage.
					Judging Criteria: Vocals, music, expressions, body language, overall impact, make-up and costumes according to the Act, stage setup, and synchronization with dialogues.<br>
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Street Play">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Street Play</Strong></center>
				Team size: Upto 12 participants from each House<br>
				Time Limit: 10-15 minutes.<br>
				1. Medium of the performance is Hindi.<br>
				2. The play should contain a social message.<br>
				3. Musical instruments using electric power are not allowed. Any other Musical instruments, including unconventional ones are allowed and will be considered as props.<br>
				4. No pre-recorded music or voice is allowed.<br>
				5. No microphones will be provided.<br>
				Judging Criteria: Creative interpretation of theme and Impact of theme, Group co-ordination, Presentation, Contact with & involvement of the Audience and Overall impact.<br>

				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Standup Comedy">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Standup Comedy</Strong></center>
				Team Size: Max 2 participants (individual) from each house.<br>
					Time limit: 5-10 min will be given to each individual.<br>
					1. As according with the title participants have to entertain humoursly.<br>
					2. Music between the acts is allowed.<br><br>

					Judging Criteria: Humor, Body Language, Presentation, etc.<br>
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Mime">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Mime</Strong></center>
				Team Size: Upto 8 participants + 4 accompanists (max)<br>
				Time limit: 12-16 minutes (includes setup and clearance time)<br>
				1. Each presentation should have a title and a theme. <br>
				2. Medium of performing the Skit should be Hindi. <br>
				3. The Skit can involve multiple scenes and blackouts.<br>
				4. Backstage voice overs or sounds or narration are allowed during the Performance.<br>
				5. Background or Pre-recorded music is allowed.<br>
				Production material provided: 1 table, 2 chairs.<br>
				Any other production material has to be brought by the teams but the Organizers reserve the right to allow its use on the stage.<br><br>
				Judging Criteria: Presentation of the theme, Group co-ordination, Dialogue Delivery and Overall impact, Acting, Make-up and Costumes according to the Act.

				]]>
			</Event>
		</theature>
		<photo>
			<Event name="Short Film Making">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Movie Making</Strong></center>
				Team Size: Unlimited as per required. <br>
					Time limit: Running time for each video (5-12min.): Maximum Fifteen (15) minutes, including any titles and/or credits. Entries longer than Fifteen (15) minutes will lead to negative marking.<br>
					Rules: <br>
					1. The Competition is open solely to original, newly-created Entries, or original, previously-created Entries which have not been distributed to the public (including, without limitation, display on the YouTube Website).<br>
					2. Members of other houses may appear in the movies but not allowed to play/have a significant role.<br>
					3. All Entries should be in Hindi (Partial use of other languages are allowed).<br>
					4. Clear Theme should be derivable from the film.<br>
					5. All entries are to be submitted on or before 30th March 2015.<br>
					6. Animation movies are allowed.<br><br>
					Judging Criteria: <br>
					1. Storytelling <br>
					2. Creativity and originality. <br>
					3. Screenplay and Actor(s) Performances. <br>
					4. Technical Execution: Camera/Sound/Lighting/Editing.<br>
					5. Overall Impression.<br>
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Photo Presentation">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Photo Presentation</Strong></center><br>
				Team Size: Unlimited as per required.<br>
				Time limit: Running time for each video (3-5min.); including any titles and/or credits.<br>
				Rules:<br>
				1. All entries are to be submitted on or before 30th March 2015.<br>
				2. Photos must be related to the Resurgence 2016.<br>
				Judging Criteria: <br><br>
				1. Creativity <br>
				2. Technical Execution: Camera/Sound/Editing.<br>
				5. Overall Impression.<br>

				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Resurgence Cover Shot">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Resurgence Cover Shot</Strong></center><br>
				1. The participants will be provided with a particular time slot and they have to take snaps related t the university such that they can be used for representing the university's glory.<br>
				2. There won't be any kind of restrictions over the area the participants have to take the Snaps.<br>
				3. The participants have to restrict the image quality of the photos to be clicked upto medium. no large above 1024x320 quality and above 12 mps will be entertained.<br>
				4. The participants are requested to bring their own DSLRs and the photos should be completely raw and no external editing will be entertained.<br>
				5. The Sd cards which have the snaps will be collected at the end of the snap session and the snaps will be collected and again the Sd cards be returned to the respective participants.<br>
				6. The best representing snaps will be selected and the respective contestant will be awarded and the so taken snaps will be demonstrated in the auditorium with the courtesy in the name of the respective winner.<br>
				7. The winner will get the chance to demonstrate the snaps in other curriculums if needed.<br>
				8. The best of the Pics will be selected for the University Magazine.<br><br>
				Judging Criteria: Impact, Composition, Technical Quality and Suitability.


				]]>
			</Event>
		</photo>
		<special>
			<Event name="Fashion Show">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Fashion Show</Strong></center>
								
				Team Size: 10 from each House, including 5 models  and 1 main designer, 1 make-up designer, 1 hair designer and 2 assistant designer.

				Rules<br><br>
				Each house has to prepare main design using dark colors according to the theme. Material may include products made from paper, plastics, rubber, etc. Use of Paper is allowed for making dresses but fabric should be used as the base and length of dress should be up to knee length and protective layers should be used as per order by the Dean of students.<br><br>

				Judging Criteria: <br>
				Use of the colors <br>
				Original and creative approach.<br>
				Overall Effect.

				Theme<br>
				Will be discussed with the committee and all the house coordinator.<br>
				]]>
			</Event>

			<Event name="Spot Hidden Talent">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Spot hidden talent</Strong></center>
								
				
					Team Size: Max 3 individuals from each house<br>
					Time Limit: 	1st round: 60 seconds<br>
							2nd round: 60 seconds<br>
					Rules:<br>
					1. Participation is open to any SMVDU student belonging to the respective house.<br>
					2. Instructions shall be provided on the spot.<br>
					Judging Criteria: Entertainment.<br>
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Mea Culpa">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Mea Culpa</Strong></center>
								
					Team Size: 	3 members team from each house.<br>
					1 prosecutor (M/F)<br>
					Time limit:	5-8 minutes for each defender<br>
					Topic: Characters will be assigned to both the members (1M+1F) of a House 3 days before the event through a raffle (chit system).<br>
					The prosecutor will coordinate the proceeding enacting the role of a trial taker.<br>
					Every House will pose only one question to each defender of the other House. For this purpose, a House will prepare 8 allegations, 2 each for the defenders of every other House. Moreover, a House is required to submit the names of four students, one for every other House, who will ask the questions.<br>
					In the last, the prosecutor can entertain at most one open question from the audience. Judges can interfere to discard any questions from the audience, if necessary.<br><br>
					Judging Criteria:<br>
						Defender<br>
					1. Argumentative value of the defence<br>
					2. Voice Modulation (including suitable use of accents), content, suitability and propriety of language<br><br>
							Prosecutor<br>
					1. Effective coordination of the proceeding<br>
					2. Presence of Mind<br>
					3. Critical Attitude<br>
				]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Youth Parliament">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Spot the hidden talent</Strong></center>
								
				Team Size:<br>
					Time Limit:<br>
					Rules:<br>
					As per National Youth Parliament Competition Scheme for Universities/Colleges by Ministry Of Parliamentary Affairs Government Of India.

				]]>
			</Event>
		</special>	
	</inter_university>
</EventSection>
