<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<EventSection>
	<inter_house>
		<literary>
			<Event name="Debate-Hindi (Single)">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Debate-Hindi (Single)</Strong></center><strong>Team Size:</strong> 2 from each House, one for the motion & the other against the motion<br/>
				<strong>Time limit:</strong> Each member will be given 4 minutes to speak and 1 minute to refute. The refutation shall begin with the last speaker. 1st warning Buzzer will be after 3 minutes.<br/>
				Topic: Issue for the Debate will be decided by the coordinators of the event.<br/>
				1.	Topic will be available on the Resurgence website 3 days prior to the event.<br/>
				2.	Medium of presentation is Hindi only.<br/>
				3.	Paper reading is not allowed. One may however refer to noted points.<br/>
				<strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Voice Modulation (including suitable use of accents), content, suitability and propriety of language<br/>
				Matter – the logical reasoning and content presented by the debater<br/>
				Manner – presentation and delivery, the style of speaking, body language.<br/>
				Method – structure and organization of the presentation made by the speakers.]]>	
			</Event>
			<Event name="Debate–English (Single)">				
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Debate-English (Single)</Strong></center><strong>Team Size:</strong> 2 from each House, one for the motion &#38; the other against the motion.<br/>
				<strong>Time limit:</strong> Each member will be given 4 minutes to speak and 1 minute to refute. The refutation shall begin with the last speaker. 1st warning Buzzer will be after 3 minutes.<br>
				<strong>Topic:</strong> Issue for the Debate will be decided by the Faculty Coordinators of the event.<br/>
				1.	Topic will be available on the Resurgence website 3 days prior to the event.<br/>
				2.	Medium of presentation is English only.<br/>
				3.	Paper reading is not allowed. One may however refer to noted points.<br/>
				<strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Voice Modulation (including suitable use of accents), content, suitability and propriety of language<br/>
				Matter: the logical reasoning and content presented by the debater<br/>
				Manner: presentation and delivery, the style of speaking and body language.<br/>
				Method: structure and organization of the presentation made by the speakers.]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Extempore (Group)">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Group Extempore</Strong></center><strong>Team Size:</strong> 3 from each House
				<strong>Time limit:</strong> 2 minutes for each participant<br/>
				1.	Topic will be announced on the spot. <br/>
				2.	For each team there will be a different topic. <br/>
				3.	The first speaker shall begin speaking after 2 minutes of getting the topic.<br/>
				4.	Each participant of a team will be given 2 minutes. <br/>
				5.	After 2 minutes, there will be a Buzzer and the next member will take over where the last speaker finishes.<br/>
				<strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Creativity, Spontaneity, Body language, Voice modulation, intensity and coverage of the content]]>

			</Event>
			<Event name="Poetry – Hindi\ English (Single)">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Poetry</Strong></center><strong>Team Size:</strong> 2 (1 for English and 1 for Hindi) from each House<br/>
				<strong>Time limit:</strong> 3-5 minutes for each recitation <br/>
				1.	Topic will be given only two hours before the event and the participant is required to write poetry in a place specified by the event coordinators. <br/>
				2.	Medium of poetry is English and Hindi(although restricted use of Urdu may be allowed).<br/>
				3.	The participant will have to submit the content of the poem in writing to the judges after the recitation.<br/>
				<strong>Judging Criteria:</strong> Choice of words, diction, creativity, and style of recitation, wit and relevance to the theme]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Youth Parliament(Group)">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Essay Writing</Strong></center><strong>Team Size:</strong><br/>
				<strong>Time Limit:</strong><br/>
				<strong>Rules:</strong><br/>
				As per National Youth Parliament Competition Scheme For Universities/Colleges by Ministry Of Parliamentary Affairs Government Of India.]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Essay Writing – Hindi\English (Single)">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Essay Writing</Strong></center><strong>Team Size: </strong>2 from each House
				<strong>Time limit:</strong> 2 hours.<br/>
				1. The topic will be announced on the spot. <br/>
				2. The essay should reflect participant’s point of view.<br/>
				3. The essay should be between 300-500 words.<br/>	
				4. The language of writing is English/Hindi.<br/>
				<strong>Judging criteria:</strong><br/>
				1.	Language<br/>
				2.	Articulation<br/>
				3.	Argumentation and Justification.<br/>
				4.	Counter arguments and their criticism.<br/>
				5.	A viable conclusion.]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Travelogue">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Travelogue</Strong></center><strong>Team Size:</strong> 3 from each house<br/>
				<strong>Time limit:</strong> 1 week<br/>
				The competition is all about presentation. Each house will have to present a travel/journey/vacation experience in the form of photographs, sketches and write-ups or using a maximum of 2 ivory sheets either in the form of a composite panel or individual sheets.. The medium of expression can be Hindi/English or both. The teams will be given 7 days to submit their presentation. Slogans and captions are also allowed. 
				“Be as much creative as you can. Use any medium.”<br/>
				<strong>Judging criteria – </strong><br/>
				1.	Overall composition<br/>
				2.	Neatness<br/>
				3.	Creativity<br/>
				4.	Presentation]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Creative Writing–Hindi\English(Group)">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Creative Writing with Flash Drama</strong></center>
				(DURING WRITING)
				<strong>Team Size:</strong> 2 from each House<br/>
				<strong>Time limit:</strong> 2 hours.<br/>
				1.	The situation/theme and first line of the story will be announced on the spot. <br/>
				2.	The participants are required to make a well-formed, original story. The situation/theme may belong to any time, any era, any place, and any culture. The level of expression must appropriate the character of the situation/theme.<br/>
				3.	The story should be of 600 – 1200 words.<br/>
				4.	The language of writing is English/Hindi.<br/>
				<strong>Judging criteria:</strong><br/>
				1.	Ability to captivate the reader till the end<br/> 
				2.	Originality and articulation.<br/>
				(DURING DRAMA)<br/>
				<strong>Team Size:</strong> 6 from each House(Including Writer)<br/>
				<strong>Time Limit:</strong> 8-12 minutes<br/>
				1.	The Script should be followed.<br/>
				2.	Medium of the performing the skit can be Hindi/English.<br/>
				3.	Use of Props are allowed.<br/>
				4.	Multiple Scenes and Blackouts are allowed during the performance.<br/>
				5.	Backstage sound/narration/music are allowed.<br/>
				6.	Disqualification on extending 3 minutes time limit.<br/>
				<strong>Judging Criteria:</strong>Acting, Presentation, Script should be followed]]>
			</Event>
			<Event name="Quiz (Group)">
				<![CDATA[<center><Strong>Quiz</Strong></center><strong>
				Team Size:</strong> 3 from each house.<br/>
				<strong>Topic:</strong> Current Affairs, History, Geography, Indian Economy, Sports, Entertainment, Indian Politics, General Science.]]>
			</Event>
		</literary>	
	</inter_house>
	<inter_university>

	</inter_university>
</EventSection>